Adebayo Amodu

E: amodu.adebayo01@gmail.com | PH: 07594 023153

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Accomplished Chemical Engineer with a tier-2 visa, open to relocation, holding a Master's degree, offering extensive industry experience in Oil & Gas, and expertise across Process Design, Process Improvement and Oil Production and Safety. Consistent at delivering complex projects in accordance to engineering standards, from performing process simulations, detailed engineering calculations and developing engineering drawings, to coordinating implementation with multi-disciplinary teams. Delivers on business goals by taking a collaborative and ethical approach.

CORE COMPETECIES

Process Engineering	Economic Decision Analysis	Project Management
Process Improvement	Engineering Management	Quality Control
Advanced Chemical Engineering	Petroleum Engineering	Report Generation
Advanced Thermodynamics	Production Engineering	Six Sigma Principles
Chemical Engineering	Reservoir Engineering	Statistical Process Control
Data Analysis	Modeling and Simulation	Transport Phenomena
Design & Analysis		

WORK EXPERIENCE

International Energy Services Limited, Nigeria

02/2017 - 03/2020

Process Engineer

- Ensured 100% of deliverables met KPIs on quality, budget and schedule by delivering in accordance to governance procedures.
- Created process specification documents (data sheets, reports/studies and calculation notes).
- Predicted design requirements by simulating processes using Aspen HYSYS, computing Heat and Material Balances.
- Drafted engineering drawings (PFD, UFD and P&IDs) using AutoCAD.
- Designed and size process equipment e.g. storage tanks, pipelines, PSVs, scrubbers, vessels and pumps.
- Established and maintained professional working relationships within the organization, with clients and stakeholders.
- Generated utility and process line lists.
- Performed design verifications in accordance to relevant standards.

African University of Science and Technology, Nigeria

03/2017 - 01/2018

Graduate Research Assistant

- Mentored students on projects and in using ECLIPSE reservoir modelling and simulation software.
- Reviewed journal papers and administered tests and exams.

Water Treatment Consultants Limited

08/2013 - 03/2015

Process Engineer

• Oversaw the strategic planning, data analysis, and management of 2 Refinery Boilers which resulted in the reduction of the corrosion rate, saving the plant money and downtime.

LEADERSHIP POSITIONS

Vice President, Society of Petroleum Engineers (SPE), African University of Science and Technology | 2015-2016 Secretary General, Nigeria Society of Chemical Engineers, Ahmadu Bello University | 2010-2011

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIP

Institute of Chemical Engineers (AMIChemE), Associate Member | 2020

CERTIFICATIONS

HSE Competency Development, Institute of Safety Professionals of Nigeria | 2013

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Petroleum Engineering, African University of Science and Technology, Nigeria | 2016 *Bachelor of Science in Engineering, Chemical Engineering*, Ahmadu Bello University, Nigeria | April 2012

TECHNICAL SKILLS

AutoCAD | Aspen HYSYS | Microsoft Office | Process Design | Process Improvement | UFD, PFD and P&ID | Equipment sizing | APIs, ASME | Fishers Specification Manager | Petroleum Experts IPM MBA | Schlumberger Eclipse | Statistical Process Control